# Melle Dijkstra

# Software Engineer Student

Application Developer • Computer Scientist

Wilgenlaan 12, Dokkum, 9103 SC The Netherlands (+31) 6 11 666 686 dev.melle@gmail.com https://melledijkstra.com

# Objective

Experienced **Software Engineer** with four years of demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Currently in the second year of study with diverse **hard** and **soft** skills developed through various projects including **Team Leadership** and **Software Architecture**. As a **proactive**, analytical, and innovative individual I would be of excellent value in an internship position at companies that search for an ambitious and **highly motivated** young professional with previous **technical experience** and someone that is eager to **learn anything** that comes on its path.

# **Education**

#### Hanze University of Applied Sciences

BSc. Computer and Information Sciences, Bachelor of Science

September 2016 - June 2020 (Anticipated), Groningen, The Netherlands

<u>Courses:</u> Website Development, Project Development, IT Service Management & Security, Data Analysis & Visualization, Algorithms & Data Structures, Network Infrastructures, Operating System Structures

#### MBO ROC Friese Poort | Application & Media Developer

September 2014 - June 2016, Leeuwarden, The Netherlands

<u>Courses:</u> Design of Applications, Realization & Documenting Applications, Implementing Applications, Maintaining Applications

# Experience

# **Bouw7** | Application Developer

December 2015 - Present, Dokkum, The Netherlands

Bouw7 creates cloud-based software solutions for construction companies. Currently, I work on the creation of the web application, provide data analysis & visualization and create 3D solutions with Autodesk software.

#### Tasks include:

- Backend PHP development (with Yii2 Framework)
- Frontend Development Javascript & CSS
- Server Configuration & Management (Linux systems)
- Autodesk Forge 3D Development
- Data Analysis & Visualization (Tableau, Google Analytics)

# Stroetenga Design | Intern Application Developer

February 2016 - June 2016, Leeuwarden, The Netherlands

Internship consisted of developing a customer portal with Zend Framework 2. Also working in a team, planning and progression evaluation every week.

#### Task included:

- Team Management
- Planning and weekly progression evaluation
- Zend Framework 2 Development

# Kweekvijver Noord | Intern Media & Application Developer

February 2015 - June 2015, Leeuwarden, The Netherlands

Internship at a creative company that develops websites, video's, documentaries, photos, animations, branding, applications and Virtual Reality solutions for various clients.

#### Tasks included:

- Creating creative solutions
- Contact with customers and getting to a solution
- ❖ Teamwork with people in different fields from Media & IT

# Common Ground Farm | Farm Assistant

July 2017 - August 2017, Saint Thomas, Ontario, The Netherlands

Worked in Canada for 5 weeks on an organic vegetable farm last summer.

#### Skills

#### Technical Skills

- C#, Java, Python
- ♦ C++ (Basic)
- Web Development (PHP, Javascript, CSS, Yii2)
- Databases (SQL)
- Algorithms & Data Structures
- ❖ WPF. JavaFX
- Mobile Android Development

- Operating Systems (Unix/Linux, Windows)
- Google Analytics, Google Webmaster (SEO)
- Network Security
- TCP/IP Network
  Programming
- ❖ gRPC

# Organizational skills

- Excellent communication skills
- Team Leadership and management skills
- Good presentation skills
- Google Suite: Sheets,
  Docs, Gmail, Calendar
- Microsoft Office 2016: Excel, Word (Advanced)

# **Honors & Awards**

#### **Finalist Skills Heroes**

One of the finalists of the Skills Heroes 2016

The Skills Heroes is a professional competition for secondary vocational education in The Netherlands. Participants go through various qualification rounds and finally the national finals, participants compete in their field to become the best in the Netherlands.